unitestudents.com 2017-09-10

# Privacy Policy | Unite Students

UNITE Group Plc (Unite Students) is committed to protecting your privacy on-line. We treat your privacy seriously and have put in place this policy to ensure we protect your personal details. We use the personal information that we collect from you in accordance with this privacy policy. We are subject to the Data Protection Legislation and are registered with the Information Commissioner's Office. This privacy policy covers visitors to the Unite Students internet site [www.unitestudents.com](http://www.unitestudents.com/).

**Who We Are  **

UNITE Integrated Solutions plc is a subsidiary of the UNITE Group plc known as Unite Students. The online services are delivered in association with carefully selected business partners. The UNITE Group is the UK's leading provider of affordable, high quality accommodation for Students and Key Workers. Please visit the 'Contact us' section for contact information on UNITE Group or alternatively visit [www.unite-group.co.uk](http://www.unite-group.co.uk/).

**The services covered by this policy  **

This policy only applies to websites created for on-line transaction, registration, booking and Customer's interaction with Unite Students, all the personal information collected by Unite Students from such services and collected from customers when they register for Unite Student's services, but does not apply to the third party companies, individuals, organisations or other websites to which our website may link to. These sites operate their own privacy policy. We urge you to read these carefully.

**What we mean by personal information  **

When we refer to personal information in this policy, we mean information that can identify you as an individual or is capable of doing so. By personal information we don't mean general, statistical, aggregated or anonymous information (the types of personal information we will collect will be information that is used for the purposes of processing your application and finding you a suitable room).

**Consent  **

Your use of our services signifies your consent to us collecting and using personal information about you as specified below in accordance with this policy. Should we choose to change our policy for any reason the changes will be notified in writing to our Customers and also updated on our Terms and Conditions. If you are an on-line Customer this policy will be applied subject to any particular limitations or preferences you made as part of the registration procedure.

**How we collect information about you  **

You may provide personal information when communicating with us. (i.e. when you fill out your registration form to become a tenant or sign up for additional services). You may order a product or a service and give your name, e-mail address, delivery address, credit or debit card number and expiry date (or relevant bank account details), so that the order can be processed and your products (or services where appropriate) delivered to you. Sometimes you may be asked for your telephone number. If you enter a competition or promotion we will ask for your name, address and e-mail address and any other relevant information. We will collect information about your tastes and preferences both when you tell us what these are and by analysis of customer traffic, including by using cookies (as described below). It may be that some of the personal information you give us (for instance about your lifestyle or health) is sensitive personal data within the meaning of the Data Protection Act 1998. Any such information ("sensitive information") will only be disclosed with your express consent. It may be that you provide to us details of credit or debit cards or bank accounts in order to make payments to us. Any such information ("confidential financial information") will be used only for the specific purpose for which it was provided.

**How we use your information  **

We may use your information to confirm that your orders have been received, to validate you as a registered Customer when using our services and calling our help desk, to prevent and detect criminal activity, fraud and misuse of or damage to our services or networks and to prosecute those responsible, or to invite you to form part of our consumer panel or research groups. We may use personal information collected about you to contact you by post, phone and electronic mail (that is email, picture, video, and SMS) about functionality changes to our web site, services or changes to our terms and conditions of use and to communicate with you about your Customer benefits and advise you regarding the use of our services, unless you opt out of such communication during the registration process (or subsequently by contacting your Unite Students City Team). We may use the information collected about you to contact you by post or phone about new offers and services offered by Unite Students. We may also contact you by electronic mail for these purposes subject to any preferences selected by you. Sometimes our Affiliated Companies and selected third parties might use the personal information collected about you to contact you by post, phone and, by electronic mail about new goods, services or offers that you might find interesting in accordance with any preferences selected by you. We may use personal information collected about you to personalise your visits to our web site and recommend goods or services to you. We also use the information to help us develop the design and layout of our web site to ensure that our sites are as useful and enjoyable as possible.

**Other information we may collect  **

We may collect traffic data related to you use and access to our services. Such data would include time spent online. We may also use this information for marketing our services and to understand and keep you informed about what is the best Internet access package for you according to your use of the services. We may provide aggregated statistics about our sales, customers, traffic patterns and other site information to third parties, but these statistics will not include any information that could personally identify you. If you are an on-line Customer, the information collected from the website is not anonymous. We use this information along with your preferences to tailor content, services and offers for you.

**Why we collect your Information  **

We will process your personal information so that: We can process your booking and any orders for goods and/or services that you place with us; We can fulfil our obligations under any contract for the supply of rented accommodation or the supply of any goods and/or services subject always to the terms and conditions relating to the supply; We can deal with the general queries that you raise from time to time by email, post or telephone etc.

**How long we keep your information  **

The periods we keep your information can vary according to the use given to the information. Unless there is a specific legal requirement to keep your information we will not keep it for longer than necessary for the purposes for which the data was collected or for which it is to be further processed.

**Disclosing your information to third parties  **

Unite Students reserves the right to access and disclose individually identifiable information to comply with applicable laws and lawful government requests, to operate its systems properly or to protect itself or its users. We may provide aggregate statistics about our sales, customers, traffic patterns and other site information to third parties, but these statistics will not include any information that could personally identify you. Subject to the choices you made during your registration and subsequently, we may disclose your information to our Affiliated Companies and selected third parties. We sometimes use other companies to provide some of our services, or to provide services to us or distribute our products. These companies can only process this information on behalf of Unite Students and will only be processed according with our instructions and applicable data protection legislation, they will not be used for sales or marketing purposes.

**How we protect your information  **

When you review your account information or order products, Unite Students offers the use of a secure server. The secure server software encrypts the information that you input before it is transmitted to us. In addition, we have strict security procedures covering the storage and disclosure of your information in order to prevent unauthorised access and to comply with the Data Protection Act 1998. This means that sometimes we may ask you for proof of identity before disclosing any personal information to you.

**Cookies explained  **

A cookie is a piece of information that is stored on your computer's hard drive by your web browser, or stored as a temporary object in your web browser for the time of that connection.

**When we use cookies  **

During the registration process we allocate cookies during the registration process for our services. These cookies will hold information collected during your registration and will allow us to recognise you as a customer and provide you with the services you require. The type we use is known as a 'session-based' cookie and is allocated to your computer only for the duration of your visit to our web site. The second type of cookie is known as a 'persistent' cookie. These cookies will remain on your computer for a period of time set for each cookie.

How they work:

  * Limit how often you see a particular advertisement or announcement on our web site
  * Identify your preferences when customising content for you
  * Provide you with relevant self-help information
  * Record how many times you visit a page or advertisement
  * Limit and record how often you can vote in our polls
  * Confirm you are a registered user and save your login details when accessing certain services on our website
  * Collect statistics on the use of our services
  * We may also use cookies and web beacons to ensure that our mailing tools are working properly

Other companies which advertise or offer their products or services on our web sites may also allocate cookies to your computer. These cookies are used:

  * To serve advertisements on our site and track whether these advertisements are clicked on by users
  * To control how often you are shown a particular advertisement
  * To tailor content to your preferences
  * To count the number of anonymous users of the site
  * To provide security within shopping baskets or transactions

The types of cookies they use and how they use the information generated by them will be governed by those companies' Privacy Policies. We have no control over these.

How you can refuse or opt out of cookies: Most browsers are set by default to accept cookies automatically, but usually you can alter the settings of your browser to prevent automatic acceptance and prompt you every time a cookie is sent to you or to allow you to choose not to receive cookies at all. For further information on cookies and how to manage them you can go to [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

**How you can manage your privacy preferences**

**Collection of information  **

We automatically log visitors domain and IP address by programming. This data is used to see where the site is being used to ensure coverage, and for click stream analysis to help better understand site usage, so that we may improve our service to you. We do not identify the user but only the computer that is being used to view the site.

**Cookies  **

Cookies are used temporarily to store information. Cookies are specific to the server that created them and cannot legally be accessed by other servers, which means they cannot be used to track your movements around the web.

**Subscribing to services  **

When requesting information, you may be asked for your e-mail address, and/or your name and postal address. The information requested is then sent to you using the personal details received. We will not pass your details to any third parties unless it is to assist us in responding to your request, comments etc.

By subscribing to a service you offer your information in return for services; you consent to such a transfer. Unite Students always provides the option to unsubscribe to services at any time.

**Security  **

Unite Students have taken all the relevant security measures to protect any personal data received from loss, misuse and alterations of customer data under our control. While we cannot guarantee that loss, misuse or alterations of data will not occur, we use our best efforts to prevent this.

**Acceptance  **

By using this site you consent to the collection and use of this information by Unite Students and to this privacy policy. If we change our privacy policy in anyway, we will post these changes on this page.

**Accessing your information  **

You may request details of the information, which we hold on you. If you wish to do this there will be a fee of £10.00. All requests to access information should be sent by email to [customerservices@unitestudents.com](mailto:customerservices@unitestudents.com).
